<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NAV Patterns Archive on AL Guidelines</title><link>https://alguidelines.dev/navpatterns/</link><description>Recent content in NAV Patterns Archive on AL Guidelines</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://alguidelines.dev/navpatterns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. Patterns</title><link>https://alguidelines.dev/navpatterns/1-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alguidelines.dev/navpatterns/1-patterns/</guid><description>Browse design patterns by tags Originally, this page was categorized set of links to subpages, but that is not necessary now with the menu system to the left.</description></item><item><title>2. Anti-Patterns</title><link>https://alguidelines.dev/navpatterns/2-anti-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alguidelines.dev/navpatterns/2-anti-patterns/</guid><description>Some of the software development practices, had not stood the test of time. Despite that, some are still being used today by developers everywhere.
&amp;ldquo;An anti-pattern (or antipattern) is a common response to a recurring problem that is usually ineffective and risks being highly counterproductive&amp;rdquo; (from Wikipedia)
Since almost the beginning of the NAV Design Patterns project, we talked about documenting the anti-patterns - but never found the time. Until, spontaneously, the April 1st 2015 article had practically wrote itself in a couple of hours, with priceless contributions coming from Andreas, Elly, Nikola - and last but not least, waldo.</description></item><item><title>3. CAL Coding Guidelines</title><link>https://alguidelines.dev/navpatterns/3-cal-coding-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alguidelines.dev/navpatterns/3-cal-coding-guidelines/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve decided to publish our current C/AL coding guidelines. They are actual, as per January 2015 when this is published (but might fall out of sync as time goes by).
You can also download the C/AL coding guidelines as pdf, all in one document. In contrast, on this wiki, the coding guidelines are published individually. The reason is: give you the chance to comment and share your oppinion on each one.</description></item><item><title>(OLD) Get Involved</title><link>https://alguidelines.dev/navpatterns/4-get-involved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alguidelines.dev/navpatterns/4-get-involved/</guid><description>Reminder, this is an ARCHIVE of the Patterns site, this information is not current. Spread the info
NAV Design Patterns are excellent materials for training and knowledge transfer. In your company, you can help new developer get to speed with NAV by recommending them to read and then present to the team one of the most common patterns: No. Series, Setup Table and definitely Hooks which will be a great investment in reducing your upgrade time.</description></item><item><title>Related Links</title><link>https://alguidelines.dev/navpatterns/related-links/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alguidelines.dev/navpatterns/related-links/</guid><description>Find below some related NAV Design Patterns links.
MSDN NAV Team Blog - posts about patterns
NAV Application Design slides from NAV TechDays conference in Antwerp, 2013
NAV Application Design movie from NAV TechDays conference in Antwerp, 2013
NAV&amp;rsquo;s Secret Code: Design Patterns of Today and Tomorrow slides from NAV TechDays conference in Antwerp, 2013</description></item></channel></rss>