<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>(OLD) Get Involved on BC AL Help</title><link>https://bcalhelp.dev/navpatterns/4-get-involved/</link><description>Recent content in (OLD) Get Involved on BC AL Help</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bcalhelp.dev/navpatterns/4-get-involved/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://bcalhelp.dev/navpatterns/4-get-involved/code-of-conduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bcalhelp.dev/navpatterns/4-get-involved/code-of-conduct/</guid><description>Find below the rules to be used when disseminating or relating to the NAV Design Patterns.
Only use materials published in text on the NAV Design Patterns Wiki site. If you received from us, any unpublished materials, please observe that they are subject to change and have not been approved for external use. When referencing a NAV Design Pattern, you must remember to also reference its author and company where the author is employed.</description></item><item><title>Patterns Authors</title><link>https://bcalhelp.dev/navpatterns/4-get-involved/patterns-authors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bcalhelp.dev/navpatterns/4-get-involved/patterns-authors/</guid><description>This is the list of people that have been part of the NAV Design Patterns team. If you would like to join the project follow the instructions provided on Be a NAV Pattern Author page.
Project administrator: Bogdana Botez.
Authors (in alphabetical order):
Abshishek Ghosh, Microsoft (4 patterns)
Using Query Objects to Detect Duplicates Blocked Entity Single-Record (Setup) Table Temporary Dataset Report Anders Larsen, Microsoft (1 pattern)</description></item><item><title>Template for writing Nav Design Patterns</title><link>https://bcalhelp.dev/navpatterns/4-get-involved/template-for-writing-nav-design-patterns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bcalhelp.dev/navpatterns/4-get-involved/template-for-writing-nav-design-patterns/</guid><description>This is a guideline, some parts are optional (if there&amp;rsquo;s no content, remove the whole paragraph).
&amp;lt;Your name here in italics, plus your company name&amp;gt;
&amp;laquo;Pattern Title&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Short, descriptive and easy to remember.
Pattern Logo Black &amp;amp; white, no text on it.
Context: Sets the stage where the pattern takes place. 1-2 sentences.
Problem: What happens before this pattern is used? How can it go wrong? 1-5 lines.
Forces: (explain why the problem is difficult to solve; state the considerations that must be taken into account when choosing a solution to a problem)</description></item></channel></rss>